Guide to the Edward E. Smuts Papers, 1945-1981 AIS.2012.07
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Urban Development Consultants, Inc., 1959-1981; VII.
  - Topical Folders, 1952-1981; 8.
    - St. John's General Hospital - Contract and Billing, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 32)
    - St. John's General Hospital – Smuts New Role, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 33)
    - St. John's Hospital – Historical Perspective, 1970-1976 (Box 23, Folder 34)
    - St. John's Hospital – Photographs and Slide Presentations, 1973-1975 (Box 23, Folder 35)
    - St. Margaret Memorial Hospital (SMMH) General, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 36)
    - SMMH - Billing, 1973-1977 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - SMMH– Board Meetings, 1975-1977 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - SMMH – Development Program for Health Care, 1975 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - SMMH – Project Manual, 1975-1977 (Box 24, Folder 4-5)
    - St. Paul Cathedral, 1973 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - St. Thomas Dairies, Ephrim Adkins, 1972-1973 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Sardinia, 1970-1972 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Schafer, Seymour - Office Building, 1980 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Schume, Mary Louise, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Scottdale County, 1964 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Service Stations Planning, 1965-1969 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Shady Side, 1968-1976 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Sharon Redevelopment Authority – Contract and Billing, 1976-1977 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Sheridan E.S./P.V. Land Management, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Short-Run Industrial Problems – Department of City Planning, 1959-1962 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Sinclair, Ian, 1975 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Skrabut, Myron – Olentangy Management Company, 1978 (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - Slop Study – Pittsburgh Follow-up, 1960-1961 (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - Smith, Larry, & Company, Inc., 1966-1968 (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - SNAP & Shadyside Coalition, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - Somerset, 1960 (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - South Craig Association, 1979-1980 (Box 24, Folder 23)
    - South Craig Street Follow-up, 1979-1980 (Box 24, Folder 24)
    - Southeast Banking Corporation, 1964-1969 (Box 24, Folder 25)
    - South Side, 1978 (Box 24, Folder 26)
    - Special Studies – Street Furniture, 1967-1968 (Box 24, Folder 27)
    - Southwestern Pennsylvania Regional Planning Commission (SPRPC) – Health Policy Institute, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 28)
    - SPRPC – Paratransit, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 29)
    - Squirrel Hill Development Area, 1970-1971 (Box 24, Folder 30)
    - Stadium Authority of Pittsburgh, 1981 (Box 24, Folder 31)
    - Steel City Electric, 1967-1969 (Box 24, Folder 32)
    - Stillson, Geoffery – Real Estate Consultant, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 33)
    - Stevenage Development Corporation, 1962 (Box 24, Folder 34)
    - Strahorn, James- Landsing Associates, 1975-1978 (Box 24, Folder 35)
    - Strawberry Way, 1968-1970 (Box 24, Folder 36)
    - Strip District, 1974-1979 (Box 24, Folder 37)
    - Surdoval, Lawrence A., 1979 (Box 24, Folder 38)
    - Swindell Dressler Company, 1974 (Box 24, Folder 39)
    - Tenant Leasing – A303 – Craft Marketing Cooperative Associates, 1978-1979 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Tenant Leasing – A340 – Katz, Eleanor – Looney Bird Gallery, 1979-1980 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Tenant Leasing – B – Machtiger, 1979 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Tenant Leasing – B311 – Jacquie's Place, 1980 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Tenant Leasing – C160 - Ronald McNeish Associates, 1978-1981 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Tenant Leasing – C317/319 – Avalance, 1979-1981 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Tentant Leasing - Scandia Shope C317/319, 1979 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Tenant Leasing – D384 – Skurka, Mary, Grace – Fabric Folio, 1978-1979 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Tennis Club Development Shadyside, 1973-1975 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Thorn, R.S. – Pitt Economic Department, 1975-1977 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Three Rivers Computer Company, unknown (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Three Rivers Improvement and Developers (TRIAD) Corporation, 1971-1972 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Texaco - Shadyside, 1979 (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Transit, Mass, and Rapid – Core Downtown Loop Analysis – Pgh. Council for Urban Transit, 1965-1969 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Transit, Mass, and Rapid – Core – SOM study, 1967 (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Trustee Education - William Metcalf – University of Minneapolis, 1978 (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Turtle Creek Model Cities Program, 1966-1968 (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Underground Wiring, 1967-1968 (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - Union Real Estate, 1976-1977 (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - United Fund, 1973-1976 (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - United States Steel Corporation, 1970 (Box 25, Folder 21)
    - University Science Center, 1969-1970 (Box 25, Folder 22)
    - University of Pittsburgh – Contract, 1975-1978 (Box 25, Folder 23)
    - University of Pittsburgh – Forbes Quadrangle, 1967 (Box 25, Folder 24)
    - University of Pittsburgh – Research Liaison, 1968-1971 (Box 25, Folder 25)
    - University of Pittsburgh – UDC Counsel Follow-up, 1970 (Box 25, Folder 26)
    - University Place – Development Rights – Mellon Site, 1960-1962 (Box 25, Folder 27)
    - University Place – Duquesne Light, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 28)
    - University Place – East of Craig – Parking, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 29)
    - University Place – Parking – Miscellaneous Filing, unknown (Box 25, Folder 30)
    - University Place – Phase II – CMU/BPE/PUT, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 31)
    - University Place – Parking -West of Craig, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 32)
    - University Place – Property 121, 1979 (Box 25, Folder 33)
    - University Plaza, 1970 (Box 25, Folder 34)
    - Urban Design Associates, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 35)
    - Urban Design Associates – Resources (Architects), 1971-1976 (Box 25, Folder 36)
    - Urban America, 1967-1969 (Box 25, Folder 37)
    - Urban Development Consultants, Inc. (UDC) General Business Files, 1962-1963 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - UDC – Associates, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - UDC – Brochures, Resumes, etc., unknown (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - UDC –Budget, 1975-1977 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - UDC – Curry Field Project – Contract and Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - UDC – Hospital Development Seminars, 1975 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - UDC – Miscellaneous, 1964-1978 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - UDC – Monetary Tracking and Taxes, 1965-1966 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - UDC – Staff, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - UDC – Projects, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - VanHorn, 1975 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - V.W. Projects, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Washington County, 1954-1959 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Walls, John, 1962-1963 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Webster Hall Program, 1975 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Weisengerg-Ford, unknown (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Western Pa. Conservancy, 1966-1970 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - Western Pennsylvania Regional Medical Program (WPRMP) Annual Report, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - Western Pennsylvania Regional Medical Program (WPRMP) Background, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - Westinghouse, 1961-1979 (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - Westinghouse – McCrady Site, 1976-1977 (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - Westinghouse – Misc. Background Info., 1959 (Box 26, Folder 22)
    - Westinghouse – Oakland Project, 1970-1971 (Box 26, Folder 23)
    - Westinghouse – Sable Site, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 24)
    - Westinghouse Tele-Computer Systems – Resources (Data Systems), 1970 (Box 26, Folder 25)
    - West Penn. Realty, 1972-1973 (Box 26, Folder 26)
    - Wilmerding, 1963-1969 (Box 26, Folder 27)
    - Wilner Building 568-5, 1977-1978 (Box 26, Folder 28)
    - Woodland Manor, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 29)
    - Work Program, November and December 1970 (Box 26, Folder 30)
    - WPRMP – Background, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 31)
    - WPRMP – UDC Reimbursements – EES, 1962-1964 (Box 26, Folder 32)
    - WPRMP – XEROX, 1964-1965 (Box 26, Folder 33)
    - WQED, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 34)
    - Yellow Cab Company, 1969 (Box 26, Folder 35)
    - Yunis, Sally - Studio Stitchery, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 36)
  - Vacant/Sensitive Properties, 1969-1981; 9.
    This series focuses on vacant and sensitive properties in relationship to potential greenway projects. The properties are predominately located in the city of Pittsburgh. Included in the files are data on potential development sites, budget reports, correspondence, land management studies, greenway proposals, block address reports, hand written notes, photographs, land maps and graphs, meeting agendas and reports.
    - All-City Data Reference, 1979 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Area Information C-2-2 Polish Hill, 1980-1981 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Area Information N-1 Northgate, 1969-1970 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Area Information N-4 Spring Hill/Spring Garden, unknown (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Area Information N-6 Herr's Island, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Area Information N-7 Northside, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Area Infromation S-1-2 and S-1-4, 1974-1980 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Area Information S-2 Elliot St., 1979 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Area Information S-3 West Point Office Park, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Area Information S-6 Southside Park, 1969 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Dan Sentz Work Program, 1979 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Foundation News Articles - J.H.Mooney, 1980-1981 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Funding, 1979 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Land Management Excutive Summary, unknown (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Land Management Program Interim Report, 1979 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - PMMP Project Implementation Reference Materials, 1974-1980 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Vacant/Sensitive Executive Summary, unknown (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - Vacant/Sensitive - Slide Show II, unknown (Box 27, Folder 18)
    - Vacant/Sensitive Program, 1979 (Box 27, Folder 19)
- Urban Redevelopment Authority, 1952-1979; VIII.
  This series documents Smuts professional activity for the Urban Redevelopment Authority of Pittsburgh. Smuts involvement includes projects that focus on transportation, land usage and development. Papers include notes, internal and external correspondence, fact sheets, meeting notes, agendas, blueprints, memos, reports and studies, project reviews, and cost analysis reports.
  - Allegheny Center Marketability Analysis, 1960 (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Balw-Knox Company, 1952-1963 (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Environmental Design – Program Proposal, 1969 (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - General, 1966-1971 (Box 27, Folder 23)
  - Hill District Recovery Program, 1969 (Box 27, Folder 24)
  - Maps/Blueprints, 1966 (Box 27, Folder 25)
  - Penn Central Railroad, 1962-1970 (Box 27, Folder 26-28)
  - Proposals and Reports on Silver Lake, Chartiers Valley, and Wilkinsburg projects, 1962-1968 (Box 27, Folder 29)
  - Transit, Mass & Rapid, 1962-1979 (Box 27, Folder 30)
  - Transit, Mass & Rapid - PBQ&D - Progress Reports, 1968 (Box 27, Folder 31)
  - Transit, Mass & Rapid - Technical Committee Minutes, 1965-1966 (Box 27, Folder 32)
  - Urban Redevelopment Authority, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 33)
  - West Point Office Park, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 34)